THIS PROGRAM CONTAINS SCENES THAT MAY
MAY OFFEND VIEWERS' SENSIBILITIES.
IT IS INTENDED FOR AN INFORMED PUBLIC.
I remember it perfectly.
It was a completely different world.
"The golden city
with superhuman inhabitants."
It was so vast, so disproportionate,
so colossal...
far more
than we could endure.
How hot it is!
Rumors spoke
of a city of gold in the depths.
Yes, someone must have come down
and sent a dispatch balloon.
What could this building
be?
- Be careful.
- I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
It's made of crystals.
- You're not hurt?
- No, I'm not hurt.
Take a look,
there's a building in the middle!
What is it?
How was it made?
A city on the surface
that has sunk?
It's completely fossilized,
or is it a mirage
created by the crystals?
I have no idea!
This place is a real mystery!
THE GLOWING CITY OF GOLD
THE CITY OF NO RETURN
Rico, sorry to break the mood.
Currents of consciousness
come together.
Let's find a safer place
to camp.
All right.
Nanatchy,
would you have a large sheet
on which to draw a map?
Your mother didn't?
No, she talks
about food.
So as not to spoil your discovery,
I suppose.
In this case, I pass in front
to observe the force field.
Give the orders, boss.
I'm a chef!
Légu, how are your wounds?
Can you watch our backs?
Yes, I'll take care of it.
The three and a half of us,
we managed to get down
without any major problems.
It can be done,
even without a White Whistle in the group.
They had to impose this rule
to make themselves important.
Ask
the next person we meet!
Without me.
It'll be someone twisted again.
The 6th level,
from which no human can return.
The non-return.
A hippodragon.
"Their poisonous scales
explode at the slightest impact.
Fighting between males
are physical and very violent.
They are stubborn
and the curse doesn't affect them."
- Can we beat it?
- On the 6th level,
one is as dangerous
as a swarm of swindlers."
No way.
Those...
seem to be magpies.
They live near geysers
and are very docile.
Near geysers?
I don't see any.
Can you eat it?
"Their fresh eggs are delicious.
Come and see for yourself!
Must be the eggs.
They're on the move!
They're not freshly laid.
Unlike Mom,
we're going to taste them freshly hatched!
Are we really going to eat this?
Where does this light come from?
What was it?
Careful, it's poison!
What is it?
Let's get out of here!
Run for it!
Is this what
your mother calls geysers?
It takes guts
to build a nest in there.
They looked like big bubbles.
May I ask
why it amuses you?
Tada!
It's strong,
for holding up.
- Is it drinkable?
- Boiled is fine.
COOKED AS LONG AS POSSIBLE
I'm so hungry,
hurry up and open them...
TASTY SMELL OF MEAT
Did it survive the baking?
He looks dead.
It's a muscular reaction.
Even after boiling,
the muscles haven't melted...
How is this possible?
I would have preferred
a freshly laid egg.
Are you serious?
You're going to eat that?
LE GOÛTEUR
Is it still moving?
Is it any good?
- Go ahead, Rico, taste it.
- Uh...
You should be able to cook this
just like last time.
What the hell are you talking about?
Yes !
No, Rico!
I don't like those things!
They are ground into powder,
the meat,
and fry!
FRIED POUSSIN À LA RICO
MORE OR LESS APPETIZING
They're still moving!
Although I have to admit
it smells great.
- Delicious!
- Yes, you get used to it.
Is it too hot?
Yes...
Great!
- It burns...
- Here, drink. Eat slowly.
it's weird,
I feel like I've eaten this before.
Not me.
It's coming back to me!
It was a foreign dish
for the fête des caverniers!
I can't remember what it's called,
but it tasted just the same!
Nut had loved it so much
that he stole the others' share.
Nut?
One of Orse's children
we told you about.
This is Nut.
Shiggy and Kiyui.
And our boss.
I hope they're okay.
Don't worry about them,
you won't see them again.
But as long as you're in the Abyss,
you're bound to the other caverniers.
If it bothers you so much,
send them a letter.
Of course!
Let's write them a letter!
Rico's gang has reached
to the 6th level.
We have to tell them about it!
Are you really going to call us
"Rico's gang"?
It's basic.
That's the best I can do right now.
Names aren't his strong point.
To me,
she gave me a dog's name.
It's perfect for you.
That's it, I'm done.
Thanks, Nanatchy!
You're including yourself too, aren't you?
That's right, dummy.
Nobody's gonna come looking for me here.
With anti-insect and bird oil,
it's ready!
- The weight should be fine.
- Yes.
Shiggy told us
that the further down you go,
the less chance the ball has of rising.
I hope they've had
the previous ones.
Do you think
they'll get this one too?
In the Abyss,
our spirit materializes.
Go ahead.
If our fears take shape
around us,
why shouldn't the same be true
for our hopes?
You have to believe.
They have received the precedents,
and they'll get this one.
Yes.
Oil does not repel
birds from the depths.
Don't be depressed about it.
Your mother must have
often messed up.
Shall we go to bed?
Yes, I'm going to sulk in bed.
What is it?
Where is it?
She's gone! Nowhere to be found!
Prushka has disappeared,
I had it on me!
Where did it go?
Someone got our ball back,
followed us while eluding
my perception
and avoided Légu's traps
to leave this message.
Who could it be
and what does he want from us?
It's metallic.
But at least it's not blood.
Some kind of ore...
And there's a smell of grease.
He didn't bother
to cover his tracks,
he underestimates us!
Let's follow his trail
and pick up Prushka.
The force field is unharmed.
It's faint,
but I can smell Prushka.
- This way.
- That's a dog.
Wait a minute, wait a minute,
Meinya found something!
What are these?
Small animal corpses?
Take a look,
their buttocks were sewn on.
There's flesh,
fat and hair.
Does it belong
to the one we're looking for?
Will it help to track him?
What's up?
I don't know, it's weird...
It's your hair
and Rico's.
Damn, he's right.
You're missing bits and pieces,
and I, tail hair.
In many places
that don't get noticed.
He did it while we were sleeping.
- What a jerk!
- It's creepy...
You don't want us
to turn back?
Let's get on with it.
That's not going to scare me!
Footprints.
A gigantic biped.
Are we looking for him?
No idea,
but we're heading in the same direction.
It follows the scents
carried by the wind.
- Shall we?
- Yes!
Is it here?
I have a feeling we're going
some great encounters.
You think it's a building?
It looks like
the corpse of a creature.
Rico, Légu.
Have you noticed?
Top right.
It's the same symbol
as on the drawing!
What does it mean?
I don't know, but...
We have to go and see!
And get Prushka!
Exactly.
It's relatively flat
until the starter,
we shouldn't have to bear the burden.
- All unknown species...
- Are you all right?
Let's make smoke
above us,
and if need be, protect us.
All right.
- Are you ready?
- All set.
Did you hear that?
- Huh? Heard what?
- Yes, but I don't know where it came from.
It sounded like a voice.
- Problem?
- Rico,
we're being watched,
but I don't know by what.
Let's keep moving,
it's dangerous to stop.
Did it belong to humans?
There's something
that repels smoke.
The force field, Nanatchy?
No,
I don't know what it is either.
I even have the impression
the force field stops here.
It's up to me, then...
Let me give it a try.
Thank you for overcoming your fear
for our sake.
That's it, I've crossed?
What's up? What's going on?
Ears, fingernails,
jaws, ribs...
What's it for?
What's all this?
What do you want?
I've never seen anything like it.
Don't provoke him, Légu!
You're also cavern makers,
aren't you?
Please forgive me.
A pleasure. My name is Majikaja.
You've come a long way.
Are you the one
who stole Prushka from me?
My white whistle, "Your Worth",
the reflection stone of life!
The stone is
in the hands of a specialist.
Please follow me.
Wait! Wait! Wait! Just a second!
We didn't know
than any human
could not leave this place
with his appearance intact.
Translation and adaptation: Adam Plaza
Spotting: Elouan Tapounie
Proofreading: Aurélie Brun
COMING SOON
THE VILLAGE OF SHADOWS